Alright
In this lesson
we're going to talk about standardizing log output
since we're about to start writing actual code
we need to write out the entire process
so we'll standardize the logs
previously, we just used print statements for logging
which means we were printing directly
What messages are you printing?
What message does he directly output?
After we standardize the output,
we will drag this time out,
if there is time,
the current time is what gets printed.
This time depends on which file you print from,
and what your log level is, right?
Then, this includes the content of the message.
After our formatted output, the log looks like this.
And we will output it to a file.
So, how exactly do we do this?
First, we need to optimize a few things.
One of these is the way we previously obtained the project directory.
It had to be called within a specific file.
After our optimization, however,
the call can be made from any file.
Let's make this change.
In this script here
Let's update this.
The principle is to search through this.
Then find these files.
For example, files like this are usually found in
Python projects.
This is a file under the top-level directory.
So its content is to locate this.
By doing this, you can find the root directory.
That's how it works.
So you can find it in any of the files.
You can always find it.
And for the second point, in this context,
we also need to update it.
This method,
it's mainly about achieving cross-platform compatibility.
Previously, we hard-coded it.
We hard-coded it with a forward slash.
Now we're using this approach.
Just update it and we're good to go.
So, what's next?
Next, we'll work on standardizing the log output.
First, we need to add this.
Let's add this dependency.
We'll add this dependency here.
In
It's not written here.
Let's write it out.
Let's put this dependency in here.
Then we'll go to the terminal and run it.
First, we need to activate it.
After activating the AI server,
we'll use pip to install the file in store bar R.
That's installed.
Once it's installed,
we'll move on to modify the configuration file.
This is basically the same as this one.
If you've worked with Spring Boot,
you know what I mean when I say Spring Boot,
you'd know how to handle standardized logging and output,
right?
Pretty much,
basically, it involves adding dependencies in Spring Boot,
writing configurations, right?
and then coding accordingly.
This is a configuration for standardized logging output.
We'll place them in both of these.
We'll put them in this template and this one as well.
Firstly, this is the configuration for the logs.
Then, the log level.
And there's also the output directory.
This output directory,
we'll use the same configuration as before.
This way, we don't need to create the directory.
We had done it previously.
He will take advantage of this convenience.
Didn't we write it down?
He will make the configuration file more convenient.
All the configuration items.
It will create the directories for us.
So we can write it directly here.
We don't need to worry about whether it has been created.
We don't need to check that anymore.
That's the benefit of it.
So, the log level is like this
Now, let's write the code
This piece of code
is where we need to create a file
create a log file
we create a Python file in UTA
and then copy this piece of code over
I'll just copy it directly
let's take a look at this piece of code
Actually, it's quite simple.
It's about creating a daily class.
Then, an initialization is carried out within it.
This initialization is mainly for standardizing the format.
We'll pass in a name.
This name refers to where you're printing.
Which file is logging the information.
You pass in the identifier for logging.
Initialization is essentially setting up the initial state.
This will eventually return a
object that is bound to that name
and then you can use this object for output
Actually, we don’t necessarily need to
know how to write it at all
This is in our video writing department.
or working on the Java backend
It’s just that
this is essentially a standard file
You can consider it as a standard
Let's take a quick look
First, we obtained a configuration here
Because we need to work with the configuration items we've obtained
These configurations
Regarding our configuration
Why did we optimize these items in YOUTUS
These elements
It's because we're working within this file
We also need to obtain this configuration.
After we get the configuration,
we then need to fetch the log option within it, right?
We just wrote this down a moment ago.
We need the level and the output directory for this.
So, we will use this.
Then,
this is where we print to the console.
That is, this terminal.
This is a format within the terminal.
Firstly, this is a color indicator.
Green.
Then, this is the time.
The time format is year, month, day, hour, minute, second.
This area here is the square brackets.
Inside here, it fetches what you pass in.
This NEMO.
And it also has a color indicator.
There's not much to say about this, really.
There's no need to memorize it.
This is just a standard output.
If you want to make changes later,
you can just make them around here.
You'll know how to do it.
This is the log level.
It's the level we pass in.
It's the current log level we're using.
There's this info
There are some errors to note
There's this debugging stuff
Then we pass our messages into here.
The messages you printed out
Are right here
Then this is the output to a file
The format for the file output is like this
There's the time and the log
Where did you print it?
And the log level as well.
And that's it for the messages.
Then, we obtain this level here.
Right here.
And ultimately, it's passed in here.
Pass the level into this.
This is output to the console.
That is, this spot here.
What we'll see here is
Then, this is the output to the file
This file is in this file directory
We have configured this directory here
Let's take a look at this directory
The configuration is in this
It's the logo in this project directory
Since we are here
We ultimately added a project directory here
This is for getting the project path.
Then it will concatenate this directory.
And then concatenate this file.
The filename is hard-coded here.
It's directly written here.
So the whole process is like this.
The object we return is bound to this object.
We can directly output it.
Let's take a look.
Let's try it again.
As you can see, the time is like this now.
This is because we are in the current state.
It's not the way of importing.
So, the target you passed in is this.
This is the name.
This is the current main.
If you call it in a different way, it would be different.
Let's try the calling method.
We're here to use this log.
We were just at this spot.
We've pretty much got the log all set up.
We can use it right here directly.
How do we use it?
First, we need to initialize it here.
When initializing, well, this initialization step.
Here we are,
that's it.
This is where we use it
Target is set to the one we just had
So let's pass this in
Then we import this
After doing this
We can use it now
Let's see how to use it
Here we can call it
For example, we need to add a member here
This is one of its member variables.
We call the info method here.
This is where we create it.
Write it down here.
AI Factory
Create an ASR instance, right?
And this part also has a significant impact.
Create a TDS instance.
Then let's take a look at this part.
In the main.** file
aren't we instantiating the factory here?
it should print this out
let's take a look at this round here
okay, let's check it out
right now, it prints in this format
the date
and this is because you're calling it through an import
so it can print this out
Where is this located?
We are in this file, right?
It prints out within this file.
The log level is set to info.
Then, this is where you can see its messages.
The color of this message is like this.
If we want to change the log level here,
we can modify it in the configuration file.
Currently, this is set to info.
Then we can change it to a different log level.
After making the change,
it will output accordingly.
For instance, if you change it to a warning level,
then the info level logs won't be output.
It will filter them out.
Currently, our log level is set to debug,
which means,
both the regular logs and the warnings,
as well as the error logs, will all be printed out.
And it also created the log file,
and printed the file content out.
Let's check here to see if it has output as well.
Here,
this is the entire file.
Since this is from China,
it won't stay like this for long, right?
Ultimately, the output should be directed to a file.
This way, if we need to check the logs later,
it will be easier to review.
This is a simple implementation of logging.
For all future print statements,
we won't need to print them the old way,
we used to print them like this, right?
From now on, we'll use this standard method,
to print logs using the logging output method.
To print logs,
That's it for this lesson.